<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A speech delivered in the Commons House of Parliament, by that judicious, and worthy gentleman, Thomas Beamount Esquire: at the presenting of the petition of the knights, gentlemen, and freeholders, of the county of Leicester, on Wednesday the 6. of November, 1644. Also a true copie of the petition it selfe, subscribed with above 2000. hands.</title>
            <author>Beamount, Thomas.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1644</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A76300</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B1630</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E16_19</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R8790</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99873401</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99873401</idno>
            <idno type="VID">125871</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A76300)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 125871)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 3:E16[19])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A speech delivered in the Commons House of Parliament, by that judicious, and worthy gentleman, Thomas Beamount Esquire: at the presenting of the petition of the knights, gentlemen, and freeholders, of the county of Leicester, on Wednesday the 6. of November, 1644. Also a true copie of the petition it selfe, subscribed with above 2000. hands.</title>
                  <author>Beamount, Thomas.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 6 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for John Thomas,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Novemb. 9. 1644.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>The petition requests the appointment of Lord Grey of Groby as virtual governor of Leicestershire.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Stamford, Henry Grey, --  Earl of, 1599?-1673.</term>
               <term>Leicester (England) --  History --  Sources --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:125871:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A SPEECH DELIVERED In the Commons Houſe of Parliament,</p>
            <p>BY That judicious, and worthy Gentleman, THOMAS BEAMOUNT Eſquire:</p>
            <p>AT The preſenting of the Petition of the Knights, Gentlemen, and Freeholders, of the County of LEICESTER,</p>
            <p>
               <hi>On Wedneſday the</hi> 6. <hi>of November,</hi> 1644.</p>
            <p>ALSO A true Copie of the Petition it ſelfe, ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcribed with above 2000. Hands.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>John Thomas.</hi> Novemb. 9. 1644.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="speech">
            <pb facs="tcp:125871:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:125871:2"/>
            <head>The Speech of THOMAS BEAMOUNT Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quire, to the Houſe of Commons, at the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſenting of Leiceſter-Shire Petition.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>SIR,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He deepe expreſsions the whole Kingdom hath received of grace and clemency from this honou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable Houſe, hath incouraged us in our great ſufferings, to make our retreat hither, our Countrey being almoſt invironed with deſtroying Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies, and our ſelves continually expoſed to loſſe and danger, theſe our miſeries (as wee humbly apprehend) taking birth eſpecially from two Cauſes.</p>
            <p>One is, our want of a chief Commander. For, whileſt the Enemy is ſpoiling our Countrey, the Officers of our Forces, being under no particular Authority, are ſo long in diſputing who ſhall go out for our defence, that before they appeare, the Enemy hath done the miſchief, and is retired.</p>
            <pb n="2" facs="tcp:125871:3"/>
            <p>The other is, our Countreyes diſacquaintance with moſt of thoſe which ſit in the Commitee, which in ſome averts, in many leſsens a free and lively adhering to them.</p>
            <p>For the common people, of which our ſtrength moſt conſiſts, do only truſt, and expect an active care from ſuch, whoſe reſidence with them hath begot affection, and eſtates amongſt them, gives them an apprehenſion that they are involved in the ſame danger with them. Our preſent Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee receive nothing but what they forcibly ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tort from the Countrey, wherein they make an unprofitable purchaſe: for, though they get ſome money, they loſe many hearts; whereas if men that have eſtates and are well known in their Countrey were joyned with them, the people would generally come in, and offer up all they have for the advancement of the publike good.</p>
            <p>For, we have men, horſes, and money left, good materialls to repair our decayed Countrey, if this honorable Parliament (the great Archite<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctors of the Commonwealth) will pleaſe to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pute us good Under-builders to prevent a ruine.</p>
            <p>In theſe clouds of trouble that darken our whole Nation, this Parliament is our onely Sun,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:125871:3"/>that diffuſeth light to the ſeverall Committees of every County; and they, like Stars, ſhould im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part their borrowed ſhine to us: but if they be unknown Starres, they do not direct, but di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtract the Pilot in his paſsage.</p>
            <p>In theſe our miſeries, as we have many ſharers, ſo (if it had been thought neceſsary) there had been many more preſenters of them to you: but we, in the name of all, do humbly invocate a gracious and ſpeedy redreſse, the unhappy di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of our Countrey prohibiting our frequent addreſses to this honoured place; where having briefly unboſomed our grievances, we humbly leave them to the wiſdome and conſideration of this honourable Parliament.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="petition">
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:125871:4"/>
            <head>To the honourable Houſe of COMMONS aſſembled in PARLIAMENT, <hi>The humble Petition of the Gentlemen, Freeholders, and beſt-affected of Leiceſterſhire,</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>Hat whereas by the gracious care and wiſdome of this ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable Houſe, in appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Gentlemen of Judgments and Eſtates of this County to ſit in a Committee for regulating, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quall diſpoſing of all affaires in it; and by ſending unto us the right honourable the Lord GREY of Grooby (who firſt reſcued us out of the hands of Malignants, made the town of Leiceſter (then ready to be ſeized on by them) a Garriſon, and gave incouragement and life to the actions of all the well-affected) with chiefe Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand of all the Military Forces of this
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:125871:4"/>County, the Officers of the Army, being un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the power of one, were kept from emulati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on and diſſention, and the hearts of the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſo inclined, that they were quickly able to reſiſt, and almoſt to ſuppreſſe the Enemy: But we are now (by leaving the beſt men of the County out of the Committee, in a late Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance for the MILITIA) fallen under the Government of ſuch, whoſe defects of num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, acquaintance amongſt us, and intereſts in the County, cannot afford us any probable hopes of preſervation, nor the Common<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wealth any conſiderable aſsiſtance; and in the unhappy abſence of the Lord GREY, moſt of our horſes and Armes are fold, our Souldiers diſperſed, and their headleſſe Officers in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinuall differences for preheminence, whileſt the Enemies are ſo much ſtrengthened and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſed, that the well-affected are daily expo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed to the loſſe of liberty, their goods to plun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, and their Rents ſequeſtred and ſeized on
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:125871:5"/>by the adverſe partie that till of late had never the boldneſſe or power to attempt it. In this ſad condition we have (under God) no refuge but to this honourable Houſe, the effects and influence of whoſe great prudence and care, the Common-wealth in generall, and our Country in particular, have ſo largely and fre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quently taſted.</p>
            <p>We do again therefore ſupplicate this honourable and great Councell, in eaſe of our great ſufferings, to ſend againe ſpeedily to us the Lord GREY, inveſted with power over the Forces of this County, that under his command the now diſhevel'd Souldiers being unanimouſly collected, we may be againe able to give lymits to the now un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bounded Enemy, and to command thoſe Gentlemen that are appointed to ſit in the Committee and do not ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peare, to repaire to the Country and to ſerve in it, and to add ſuch Gentlemen of knowne integrity and intereſt in the Country, as may ſo generally draw the affections of this County that we may the ſooner be wholly freed both of theſe great miſeries and their Authours.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>And we ſhal have alwaies cauſe to pray for the contingance of happy ſucceſſe to this juſt, and honourable Parliament.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
